Guide to the David Gordon papers,1960-1990.
Gordon David, Papers
- New School Debate: "Exploration In Economics", 1993 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- EEA, NY, March 1992 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Empirical Activities (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Various Articles By Gordon (Box 8, Folder 32)
- Various ideas of Gordon, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 36)
- Various Articles By Gordon, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 37)
- Seminar: "Marxism And Socialism: Whats Left After The Collapse Of The Soviet System", April 1992 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Talk Notes: "A Risign Tide Lifts All Boats- But What Raises The Tides?", May 1992 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- David Gordon's self-description for entry in Biographical Dictionary Of Dissenting Economists, July 1990 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Various readings related to course work, 1986-1988,1993 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- NYU Conference related mailings, September 1988 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Gender Seminar, IAS, Princeton, April 1988 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Talks Given By Gordon, 1989,1991 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- URPE Econometrics: "Refresher" Course In Econometrics, August 1989 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Papers Related To Analytics (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Seminar: "Keeping Tabs On The Class Struggle", 1986 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Papers Related To Model Structure, March 1991 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Papers and Research Related To Social Variables (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Work on macroeconomics, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Miscellanous Letters, 1980s (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Research by Harrison: "Globalization of Production", February 1983 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Distribution, Savings And Investment: A Macroeconomic Exploration Of Post War Economy", April 1991 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Materials: "Who Bosses Whom?", January 1989, January 1990 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Different versions of "Globalization Of Production", 1984 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- QDOT: 1900s Data (Box 9, Folder 19)
- QDOT: 1900s Metrics (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Proof Copy Of "The New Palgrave", 1986 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Research on "Capacity Utilization", August 1989 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Gordon's work at Macarthur Foundation, Febrauary 1993 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Gordon's work on macroeconomics (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Loose Macro Model (Box 9, Folder 25)
- Labor Supply Statistics, 1978-1987 (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Gordon's work on macroeconomics, April 1991 (Box 9, Folder 27)
- Work on Inequality at Macarthur Foundation, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 28)
- NSF Proposal, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 29)
- NSF Proposal Reviews, April 1986 (Box 9, Folder 30)
- NSF Project Summary, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 31)
- NSF Grant Papers, 1986-1991 (Box 9, Folder 32)
- Weisskopf Proposal, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 33)
- School Of Social Sciences, IAS Papers, November 1987 (Box 9, Folder 34)
- Various Speeches Of Gordon, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 39)
- Gordon's Personal Materials, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 40)
- Gordon' s Personal Materials, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 41)
- Gordon' s Personal Materials, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 42)
- Gordon' s Personal Materials, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 43)
- Notes on "Productivity Growth in 1980s", January 1990 (Box 9, Folder 44)
- Book Proposal: "Dirt Wages, Bloated Bureaucracies", March 1994 (Box 9, Folder 45)
- NY Times Editorial Opinion Article: "Its Slumping Wages, Stupid!", October 1994 (Box 9, Folder 46)
- List Of Talks And Materials, August 1995 (Box 9, Folder 47)
- Questionanaire on Low Wages In Business, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 48)
- Papers Related To Students' Dissertations (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Epilogue And Preface To French Edition Of "Beyond The Waste Land", May 1984 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Preface To UK Edition Of "Beyond The Waste Land", May 1985 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Epilogue To UK Edition Of "Beyond The Waste Land", June 1985 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Court Case of United Steel Workers Of America, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Political Economy For Workers, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Political Economy For Workers Part I, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Gordon's sworn affidavit (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Political Economy For Workers Part II, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Political Economy For Workers Part III, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Towards A Critique Of Capitalopolosis: Capitalism And Urban Development In US, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Understanding The Spatial Crisis (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Papers on Labor Market Stratification, 1970s (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Workbook Drafts (Box 10, Folder 20)
- "Labor Market Stratification" related responses and connections, 1970s (Box 10, Folder 21)
- Marxian Analysis Of City And Country Chapter 1, October 1976 (Box 10, Folder 27)
- Marxian Analysis Of City And Country Chapter 2, October 1976 (Box 10, Folder 28)
- Various Issues Of "The Nation", 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 31)
- Promotion Of "Beyond The Waste Land", 1983 (Box 10, Folder 32)
- Research Related To "Political Economy For Workers" (Box 10, Folder 34)
- Papers Related To Job Market, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 35)
- GE 110 Course Syllabus (Box 10, Folder 36)
- Phd Exam Paper, Summer 1992 (Box 10, Folder 37)
- Various Reviews On "Segmented Work, Divided Workers", 1980s (Box 10, Folder 38)
- Papers Related To Gordon's Students, 1989-1992 (Box 10, Folder 41)
- Papers Related To Conference On "Labor Market Segmentation", 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 47)
- URPE Material In West Virginia, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 48)
- Correspondence and Memos
- Correspondence at IAS, Princeton, NJ, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1980-1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1991-1996 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Correspondence: "The Atlantic", 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Correspondence: "Review of Radical Political Economics", 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Replies to :"Do We Need To Be No.1 ?" in "The Atlantic", 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Memos, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Correspondence: Bowles, Weisskopf and Gordon, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Correspondence: Bowles, Weisskopf and Gordon, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Correspondence: Sabbatical (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Correspondence: Scouting, 1989-1991 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Correspondence on Labor Market Segmentation, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Yale Course Business Correspondence, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Correspondence related to printing costs of "Whats Wrong With US Economy?", 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Urban Economics Text Business Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 5, Folder 25)
- "Problems In Political Economy: An Urban Perspective"- Business Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 1)
- "Problems In Political Economy: An Urban Perspective"- Permissions Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 2)
- "Problems In Political Economy: An Urban Perspective"- Editorial Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 4)
- "Problems In Political Economy: An Urban Perspective Second Edition"- Business Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Correspondence Related to Utah Conference, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Correspondence Related To Workplace Conference, May 1993 (Box 7, Folder 49)
- Correspondence With Clinton Administration, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 50)
- Correspondence Related to Investment Journal, 1990-1995 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Miscellanous Correspondence of Bowles, Weisskopf and Gordon, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 35)
- Mailings To Bowles And Weisskopf, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 36)
- Correspondence on "Rethinking Marxism" And "Beyond The Waste Land", 1987 (Box 9, Folder 37)
- Bowles, Weisskopf, Gordon Correspondence, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 38)
- Business Correspondence, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 26)
- Correspondence on "Income And Welfare in NYC", 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 29)
- Correspondence for "Segmented Work, Divided Workers", 1980s (Box 10, Folder 40)
- Correspondence and Comments On "From Steam Whistles To Coffee Breaks", 1970-1971 (Box 10, Folder 43)
- Correspondence On "Taxation Of The Poor And The Normative Theory Of Tax Incidence", 1970s (Box 10, Folder 44)
- Correspondence On "Economic Theories Of Poverty And Underemployment", 1970s (Box 10, Folder 45)
- Correspondence On "Economic Theories Of Poverty And Underemployment", 1970s (Box 10, Folder 46)
- Correspondence And Comments On The Book "Economic Theories Of Poverty And Underemployment", 1970s (Box 10, Folder 49)
- Books
- Prokla 99, June 1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Fernando Brandel Center Preview, Spring 1991 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Social Research, Fall 1993 (Box 5, Folder 31)
- Revue Politique, July-August 1993 (Box 5, Folder 32)
- Political Economy Of The New School, January 1980 (Box 5, Folder 39)
- Review Of Radical Political Economics, Spring/Summer 1988 (Box 5, Folder 41)
- Monthly Review, July-August 1976 (Box 5, Folder 42)
- Dissent, Winter 1972 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- The Harvard Review "Revolution", 1966 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Contention, Fall 1993 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Review, Winter 1994 (Box 8, Folder 7)